<GLOSSARY>
    <entry>
        <key>Abortifacient</key>
	<def>Any agent which may produce abortion.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Cancer</key>
	<def>A broad group of diseases involving unregulated cell growth. In cancer, cells divide and grow uncontrollably, forming malignant tumours, and invading nearby parts of the body.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Carcinogenic</key>
	<def>Having the potential to cause cancer.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Chemotherapeautics</key>
	<def>The treatment of cancer using specific chemical agents or drugs that are selectively destructive to malignant cells and tissues.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Chemotherapy</key>
	<def>The treatment of cancer with one or more cytotoxic anti-neoplastic drugs as part of a standardized regimen.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Clastogenic</key>
	<def>Having the potential to cause disruption or breakage of chromosomes.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Cytotoxic</key>
	<def>Detrimental or destructive to cells.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Dose</key>
	<def>A specified quantity of a therapeutic agent, such as a drug or medicine, prescribed to be taken at one time or at stated intervals.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Embryo-lethal</key>
	<def>Having the potential to cause death of the embryo.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Embryotoxic</key>
	<def>Causing injury to the embryo, which may result in death or abnormal development of a part due to entering the placental circulation.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Fetotoxic</key>
	<def>A substance poisonous to the fetus.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Half-life</key>
	<def>The time required for half the quantity of a drug or other substance deposited in a living organism to be metabolised or eliminated by normal biological processes.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Inducer</key>
	<def>A substance that induces, especially a substance that is capable of activating transcription from specific genes within a cell.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Infarction</key>
	<def>Tissue death (necrosis) caused by a local lack of oxygen, due to an obstruction of the tissue's blood supply.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Inhibitor</key>
	<def>A substance that reduces or suppresses the activity of another substance (such as an enzyme).</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Leukemia</key>
	<def>Cancer of the blood or bone marrow characterized by an abnormal increase of immature white blood cells called "blasts".</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Malignant</key>
	<def>Very virulent or infectious.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Medical protocol</key>
	<def>Medical guidelines for a medical treatment. It usually includes a treatment plan, summarized consensus statements and addresses practical issues.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Metastasis</key>
	<def>The spread of a cancer from one organ or part to another non-adjacent organ or part.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Mutagenic</key>
	<def>A substance which may cause mutation.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Oncology</key>
	<def>The study and treatment of tumours.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Radiation therapy</key>
	<def>The medical use of ionizing radiation, generally as part of cancer treatment to control or kill malignant cells.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Risk stratification</key>
	<def>A statistical process to determine detectable characteristics associated with an increased chance of experiencing unwanted outcomes.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Substrate</key>
	<def>The reactant which is consumed during a catalytic or enzymatic reaction.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Teratogenic</key>
	<def>Having the potential to cause congenital abnormalities or birth defects.</def>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <key>Toxicity</key>
	<def>The degree to which a substance can damage an organism.</def>
    </entry>
</GLOSSARY>